<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:cb="http://www.cbwiki.net/wiki/index.php/Specification_1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns# rdf.xsd"><channel rdf:about="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/"><title>FRB: DDP: Money Stock Measures (H.6)</title><link>http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html</link><description>This feed provides information about Money Stock Measures data from the Federal Reserve Board's H.6 release available through the Data Download Program (DDP).</description><items><rdf:Seq><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#1217" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#1194" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#1057" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#890" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#615" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#485" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#462" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#456" /></rdf:Seq></items><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:date>2011-05-10T08:00:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:publisher>Federal Reserve Board</dc:publisher></channel><item rdf:about="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#1217"><title>MONEY STOCK REVISIONS</title><link>http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#1217</link><description>The Federal Reserve revised its measures of the money stock and their components to incorporate updated seasonal factors and a new quarterly benchmark.   This release includes seasonally adjusted measures of the monetary aggregates and components produced with revised seasonal factors, which were derived from data through December 2015 and estimated using the X-12-ARIMA procedure.[1] While the updated seasonal factors resulted in revisions to the growth rates of seasonally adjusted M2 for individual months in 2015, the growth rates for seasonally adjusted M2 in the first and second half of 2015 were roughly unchanged.  This release also includes a new quarterly benchmark, which incorporates minor revisions to data reported in the quarterly deposit reports, and takes account of deposit data from Call Reports for banks and thrift institutions that are not weekly or quarterly deposit reporters.[2]   These revisions to deposit data start in 2012.  In addition, this release incorporates data from Call Reports on the amount of small-denomination time deposits held in individual retirement accounts (IRAs) and Keogh accounts; related revisions to deposit data start in 2015.  Likewise, the benchmark incorporates revisions to IRA and Keogh balances held at retail and institutional money market mutual funds; these revisions to data on money market mutual funds begin in 2015.  This release also incorporates the receipt of historical information from other sources of data. The effects of both the revisions to seasonal factors and the new quarterly benchmark on the growth rates of M1 and M2 are outlined in appendix tables 6 and 7. Historical data, updated each week, are available with the H.6 statistical release at www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/statisticsdata.htm.--------------------[1] Information on the seasonal adjustment procedure is available on the U.S. Census Bureau website at https://www.census.gov/srd/www/x13as.[2] "Call Reports" refers to the commercial bank Consolidated Reports of Condition and Income (FFIEC 031 and 041; OMB No. 7100-0036) and the credit union Statement of Financial Condition (NCUA 5300/5300SF; OMB No. 3133-0004).</description><dc:date>2016-01-28T16:30:00-05:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>MONEY STOCK REVISIONS</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-01-28T16:30:00-05:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>H6</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#1194"><title>Removal from List of Principal Federal Economic Indicators</title><link>http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#1194</link><description>Effective January 1, 2016, the Federal Reserve Board's Statistical Release "Money Stock Measures" (the H.6) has been removed from the Office of Management and Budget's list of Principal Federal Economic Indicators. The release will not change in any other way; the removal of the Principal Federal Economic Indicator designation will not affect the contents of the release, or the manner of its publication. The H.6 will still be released every Thursday, unless that Thursday is a federal holiday, in which case the release will be issued the next business day.</description><dc:date>2016-01-07T16:30:00-05:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>Removal from List of Principal Federal Economic Indicators</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-01-07T16:30:00-05:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>H6</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#1057"><title>Removal from List of Principal Federal Economic Indicators</title><link>http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#1057</link><description>Effective January 1, 2016, the Federal Reserve Board's Statistical Release "Money Stock Measures" (the H.6) will be removed from the Office of Management and Budget's list of Principal Federal Economic Indicators. The release will not change in any other way; the removal of the Principal Federal Economic Indicator designation will not affect the contents of the release, or the manner of its publication. The H.6 will still be released every Thursday, unless that Thursday is a federal holiday, in which case the release will be issued the next business day.</description><dc:date>2015-10-01T17:00:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>Removal from List of Principal Federal Economic Indicators</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2015-10-01T17:00:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>H6</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#890"><title>Money Stock Revisions</title><link>http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#890</link><description>For release at 4:30 p.m. EST January 22, 2015  The Federal Reserve revised its measures of the money stock and their components to incorporate updated seasonal factors and a new quarterly benchmark.  This release includes seasonally adjusted measures of the monetary aggregates and components produced with revised seasonal factors, which were derived from data through December 2014 and estimated using the X-12-ARIMA procedure.[1]  The revisions to the seasonal factors resulted in a lower growth rate for seasonally adjusted M2 in the first half of 2014 and a higher growth rate for seasonally adjusted M2 in the second half.This release also includes a new quarterly benchmark, which incorporates minor revisions to data reported in the quarterly deposit reports, and it takes account of deposit data from Call Reports for banks and thrift institutions that are not weekly or quarterly deposit reporters.[2]  These revisions to deposit data start in 2013.  In addition, this release incorporates data from Call Reports on the amount of small-denomination time deposits held in individual retirement accounts (IRAs) and Keogh accounts; related revisions to deposit data start in 2014.  Likewise, the benchmark incorporates revisions to IRA and Keogh balances held at retail and institutional money market mutual funds; these revisions to data on money market mutual funds begin in 1996.  This release also incorporates the receipt of historical information from other sources of data.The effects of both the revisions to seasonal factors and the new quarterly benchmark on the growth rates of M1 and M2 are outlined in appendix tables 6 and 7.Historical data, updated each week, are available with the H.6 statistical release at www.federalreserve.gov/releases.---------[1]  Information on the X-12-ARIMA procedure is available on the U.S. Census Bureau website at www.census.gov/srd/www/x12a. [2]  "Call Reports" refers to the commercial bank Consolidated Reports of Condition and Income (FFIEC 031 and 041; OMB No. 7100-0036) and the credit union Statement of Financial Condition (NCUA 5300/5300SF; OMB No. 3133-0004). </description><dc:date>2015-01-22T16:30:00-05:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>Money Stock Revisions</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2015-01-22T16:30:00-05:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>H6</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#615"><title>Money Stock Revisions</title><link>http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#615</link><description>The Federal Reserve has revised the measures of the money stock and its components to incorporate the results of the Federal Reserve's annual review of seasonal factors and a new quarterly benchmark. This release includes revised monthly and weekly seasonal factors as well as comparisons of the revised monetary aggregates with previously published data. The revisions to the seasonal factors resulted in a lower growth rate for seasonally adjusted M2 in the first half of 2012 and a higher growth rate for seasonally adjusted M2 in the second half.The benchmark incorporates minor revisions to data reported in the quarterly deposit reports, and it takes account of deposit data from Call Reports for banks and thrift institutions that are not weekly or quarterly deposit reporters. These revisions to deposit data start in 2011. In addition, this release incorporates data from Call Reports on the amount of small-denomination time deposits held in individual retirement accounts (IRAs) and Keogh accounts; related revisions to deposit data start in 2011. The benchmark also incorporates revisions to IRA and Keogh balances held at retail and institutional money market mutual funds; these revisions to data on money market mutual funds begin in 2007. This release also incorporates the receipt of historical information from other sources of data. Seasonally adjusted measures of the monetary aggregates and components incorporate revised seasonal factors, which were derived from data through December 2012. Monthly seasonal factors were estimated using the X-12-ARIMA procedure. The effects of both the new benchmark and the revisions to seasonal factors on the growth rates of M1 and M2 are outlined in appendix tables 6 and 7. Historical data, updated each week, are available with the H.6 statistical release at www.federalreserve.gov/releases. </description><dc:date>2013-01-17T16:30:00-05:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>Money Stock Revisions</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2013-01-17T16:30:00-05:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>H6</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#485"><title>Money Stock Revisions</title><link>http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#485</link><description>The Federal Reserve has revised the measures of the money stock and its components to incorporate the results of the Federal Reserve's annual review of seasonal factors and a new quarterly benchmark. This release includes revised monthly and weekly seasonal factors as well as comparisons of the revised monetary aggregates with previously published data. The revisions to the seasonal factors resulted in a higher growth rate for seasonally adjusted M2 in the first half of 2011 and a lower growth rate for seasonally adjusted M2 in the second half. The benchmark incorporates minor revisions to data reported in the weekly and quarterly deposit reports, and it takes account of deposit data from Call Reports for banks and thrift institutions that are not weekly or quarterly deposit reporters. These revisions to deposit data start in 2002. In addition, this release incorporates data from Call Reports on the amount of small-denomination time deposits held in individual retirement accounts (IRAs) and Keogh accounts; related revisions to deposit data start in 2006. The benchmark also incorporates revisions to IRA and Keogh balances held at retail and institutional money market mutual funds; these revisions to data on money market mutual funds begin in 1996. This release also incorporates the receipt of historical information from other sources of data. Seasonally adjusted measures of the monetary aggregates and components incorporate revised seasonal factors, which were derived from data through December 2011. Monthly seasonal factors were estimated using the X-12-ARIMA procedure. The effects of both the new benchmark and the revisions to seasonal factors on the growth rates of M1 and M2 are outlined in appendix tables 6 and 7. Historical data, updated each week, are available with the H.6 statistical release at www.federalreserve.gov/releases. </description><dc:date>2012-01-19T16:30:00-05:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>Money Stock Revisions</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2012-01-19T16:30:00-05:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>H6</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#462"><title>New graphics options are now available from the Data Download Program (DDP)</title><link>http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#462</link><description>Users can now view plotted data as column charts, and add U.S. recession shading, while using the "View chart" function of the Data Download Program (DDP). </description><dc:date>2011-11-08T15:00:00-05:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>New graphics options are now available from the Data Download Program (DDP)</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2011-11-08T15:00:00-05:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>H6</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#456"><title>Money Stock Measure data are now available from the interactive Data Download Program</title><link>http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/H6.html#456</link><description>For release at 4:30 P.M. EDT October 27, 2011 Data from the Federal Reserve Board's H.6 statistical release, "Money Stock Measures," are now available through the Data Download Program (DDP). The DDP provides interactive access to Federal Reserve statistical data in a variety of formats, including XML, and is available at http://www.federalreserve.gov/datadownload/. The H.6 statistical release is typically published on Thursday, generally at 4:30 p.m. ET. Data from the release will be available from the DDP generally 15 to 30 minutes thereafter. </description><dc:date>2011-10-27T16:30:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>Money Stock Measure data are now available from the interactive Data Download Program</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2011-10-27T16:30:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>H6</cb:keyword></cb:news></item></rdf:RDF>