<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:cb="http://www.cbwiki.net/wiki/index.php/Specification_1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns# rdf.xsd"><channel rdf:about="http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/"><title>FRB: International Finance Discussion Papers</title><link>http://www.federalreserve.gov/feeds/</link><description>Staff working papers in the International Finance Discussion Paper (IFDP) series are preliminary materials circulated to stimulate discussion and critical comment. The analyses and conclusions set forth are those of the authors and do not indicate concurrence by other members of the research staff or the Board of Governors. References in publications to the International Finance Discussion Paper series (other than acknowledgment) should be cleared with the author(s) to protect the tentative character of these papers</description><items><rdf:Seq><rdf:li rdf:resource="/apps/fof/default.aspx" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161174" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161173" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161172" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161171" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161170" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161169" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161168" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161167" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161166" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161165" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="/apps/fof/default.aspx" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161163" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161162" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161161" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="/apps/fof/default.aspx" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161159" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161158" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161157" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161156" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151155" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151154" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151153" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151152" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151151" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151150" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151148" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151147" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151146" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151145" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151144" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151143" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151142" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151141" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151140" /><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2015/index.htm#20151139" /></rdf:Seq></items><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:date>2015-08-25T09:00:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:publisher>Federal Reserve Board</dc:publisher></channel><item rdf:about="/apps/fof/default.aspx"><title>IFDP 2016-1175: Estimating Dynamic Macroeconomic Models: How Informative Are the Data?</title><link>/apps/fof/default.aspx</link><description>Daniel O. Beltran and David Draper | Central banks have long used dynamic stochastic general equilibrium (DSGE) models, which are typically estimated using Bayesian techniques, to inform key policy decisions. This paper offers an empirical strategy that quantifies the information content of the data relative to that of the prior distribution. Using an off-the-shelf DSGE model applied to quarterly Euro Area data from 1970:3 to 2009:4, we show how Monte Carlo simulations can reveal parameters for which the model's structure obscures identification. By integrating out components of the likelihood function and conducting a Bayesian sensitivity analysis, we uncover parameters that are weakly informed by the data. The weak identification of some key structural parameters in our comparatively simple model should raise a red flag to researchers trying to draw valid inferences from, and to base policy upon, complex large-scale models featuring many parameters.</description><dc:date>2016-08-01T14:15:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1175: Estimating Dynamic Macroeconomic Models: How Informative Are the Data?</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-08-01T14:15:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161174"><title>IFDP 2016-1174: Predictability of Growth in Emerging Markets: Information in Financial Aggregates</title><link>https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161174</link><description>Ayelen Banegas | This paper tests for predictability of output growth in a panel of 22 emerging market economies. We use pooled panel data methods that control for endogeneity and persistence in the predictor variables to test the predictive power of a large set of financial aggregates. Results show that stock returns, the term spread, default spreads and portfolio investment flows help predict output growth in emerging markets. We also find evidence that suggests that global aggregates such as the performance of commodity markets, a cross-sectional firm size factor, and returns on the market portfolio contain information about the future state of the economy. We benchmark our results against those from the U.S. and find that there are differences in the ability of financial markets in predicting economic growth. Our results generalize to emerging markets previous findings in the empirical macro-finance literature on the linkages between financial market performance and the real economy.</description><dc:date>2016-07-29T09:20:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1174: Predictability of Growth in Emerging Markets: Information in Financial Aggregates</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-07-29T09:20:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161173"><title>IFDP 2016-1173: Oil Price Elasticities and Oil Price Fluctuations</title><link>https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161173</link><description>Dario Caldara, Michele Cavallo, and Matteo Iacoviello | We study the identification of oil shocks in a structural vector autoregressive (SVAR) model of the oil market. First, we show that the cross-equation restrictions of a SVAR impose a nonlinear relation between the short-run price elasticities of oil supply and oil demand. This relation implies that seemingly plausible restrictions on oil supply elasticity may map into implausible values of the oil demand elasticity, and vice versa. Second, we propose an identification scheme that restricts these elasticities by minimizing the distance between the elasticities allowed by the SVAR and target values that we construct from a survey of relevant studies. Third, we use the identified SVAR to analyze sources and consequences of movements in oil prices. We find that (1) oil supply shocks and global demand shocks explain 50 and 35 percent of oil price fluctuations, respectively; (2) a drop in oil prices driven by supply shocks boosts economic activity in advanced economies, whereas it depresses economic activity in emerging economies; and (3) the selection of oil market elasticities is essential for understanding the source of oil price movements and to measuring the multipliers of oil prices on economic activity.</description><dc:date>2016-07-18T12:50:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1173: Oil Price Elasticities and Oil Price Fluctuations</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-07-18T12:50:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161172"><title>IFDP 2016-1172: Unconventional Monetary Policy and International Risk Premia</title><link>https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161172</link><description>John H. Rogers, Chiara Scotti, and Jonathan H. Wright | We assess the relationship between monetary policy, foreign exchange risk premia and term premia at the zero lower bound. We estimate a structural VAR including U.S. and foreign interest rates and exchange rates, and identify monetary policy shocks through a method that uses these surprises as the crucial "external instrument" that achieves identification without having to use implausible short-run restrictions. This allows us to measure effects of policy shocks on expectations, and hence risk premia. U.S. monetary policy easing shocks lower domestic and foreign bond risk premia, lead to dollar depreciation and lower foreign exchange risk premia. We present some evidence that U.S. monetary policy easing surprises at the ZLB shift options-implied skewness in the direction of dollar depreciation and also reduce the demand for the liquidity of short-term U.S. Treasuries. Both of these channels should lower foreign exchange risk premia.</description><dc:date>2016-06-30T11:10:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1172: Unconventional Monetary Policy and International Risk Premia</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-06-30T11:10:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161171"><title>IFDP 2016-1171: The Effect of Monetary Policy on Housing Tenure Choice as an Explanation for the Price Puzzle</title><link>https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161171</link><description>Daniel A. Dias and Joao B. Duarte | In this paper we provide an alternative explanation for the price puzzle (Sims 1992) based on the effect of monetary policy on housing tenure choice and the weight of the shelter component in overall CPI. In the presence of nominal or financial frictions, when interest rates increase, the real cost of owning a house increases, and this increase may make some people prefer to rent instead of buying. This change in consumption behavior increases the price of rents relative to other goods. Starting in 1983, homeownership costs are based on a measure of implied owner equivalent rent, which is calculated using observed house rents. This change implies that, directly and indirectly, prices in the rental market almost entirely command the shelter component of CPI, which weighs around 30% in the overall index. When we take these two pieces into account and use CPI net of shelter services as a measure of inflation, we obtain impulse responses of prices to a monetary contraction shock more in line with what is predicted by theory. In addition, our results also suggest that inflation is much less persistent than what is implied by analyses using a measure of inflation that includes shelter services. Our results pass a long list of robustness check exercises and compare well against other explanations of the price puzzle.</description><dc:date>2016-06-30T11:10:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1171: The Effect of Monetary Policy on Housing Tenure Choice as an Explanation for the Price Puzzle</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-06-30T11:10:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161170"><title>IFDP 2016-1170: What Determines the Composition of International Bank Flows?</title><link>https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161170</link><description>Friederike Niepmann and Cornelia Kerl | This paper studies how frictions to foreign bank operations affect the sectoral composition of banks' foreign positions, their funding sources and international bank flows. It presents a parsimonious model of banking across borders, which is matched to bank-level data and used to quantify cross-border frictions. The counterfactual analysis shows how higher barriers to foreign bank entry alter the composition of international bank flows and may reverse the direction of net interbank flows. It also highlights that interbank lending and lending to non-banking firms respond differently to changes in foreign and domestic conditions. Ultimately, the analysis suggests that policies that change cross-border banking frictions and, thereby, the composition of banks' foreign activities affect how shocks are transmitted across borders.</description><dc:date>2016-06-27T13:20:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1170: What Determines the Composition of International Bank Flows?</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-06-27T13:20:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161169"><title>IFDP 2016-1169: Changes in Prudential Policy Instruments--A New Cross-Country Database</title><link>https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161169</link><description>Eugenio Cerutti, Ricardo Correa, Elisabetta Fiorentino, and Esther Segalla | This paper documents the features of a new database that focuses on changes in the intensity in the usage of several widely used prudential tools, taking into account both macro-prudential and microprudential objectives. The database coverage is broad, spanning 64 countries, and with quarterly data for the period 2000Q1 through 2014Q4. The five types of prudential instruments in the database are:
capital buffers, interbank exposure limits, concentration limits, loan to value (LTV) ratio limits, and reserve requirements. A total of nine prudential tools are constructed since some useful further decompositions are presented, with capital buffers divided into four sub-indices: general capital requirements, real state credit specific capital buffers, consumer credit specific capital buffers, and other
specific capital buffers; and with reserve requirements divided into two sub-indices: domestic currency capital requirements and foreign currency capital requirements. While general capital requirements
have the most changes from the cross-country perspective, LTV ratio limits and reserve requirements have the largest number of tightening and loosening episodes. We also analyze the instruments' usage in relation to the evolution of key variables such as credit, policy rates, and house prices, finding substantial differences in the patterns of loosening or tightening of instruments in relation to business and financial cycles.</description><dc:date>2016-06-17T14:15:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1169: Changes in Prudential Policy Instruments--A New Cross-Country Database</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-06-17T14:15:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161168"><title>IFDP 2016-1168: Raising an Inflation Target: the Japanese Experience with Abenomics</title><link>http://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161168</link><description>Andrea De Michelis and Matteo Iacoviello | This paper draws from Japan's recent monetary experiment to examine the effects of an increase in the inflation target during a liquidity trap. We review Japanese data and examine through a VAR model how macroeconomic variables respond to an identified inflation target shock. We apply these findings to calibrate the effect of a shock to the inflation target in a new-Keynesian DSGE model of the Japanese economy. We argue that imperfect observability of the inflation target and a separate exchange rate shock are needed to successfully account for the behavior of nominal and real variables in Japan since late 2012. Our analysis indicates that Japan has made some progress towards overcoming deflation, but further measures are needed to raise inflation to 2 percent in a stable manner.</description><dc:date>2016-06-01T14:33:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1168: Raising an Inflation Target: the Japanese Experience with Abenomics</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-06-01T14:33:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161167"><title>IFDP 2016-1167: Doves for the Rich, Hawks for the Poor? Distributional Consequences of Monetary Policy</title><link>/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161167</link><description>Nils Gornemanny, Keith Kuester, and Makoto Nakajima | We build a New Keynesian business-cycle model with rich household heterogeneity. A central feature is that matching frictions render labor-market risk countercyclical and endogenous to monetary policy. Our main result is that a majority of households prefer substantial stabilization of unemployment even if this means deviations from price stability. A monetary policy focused on unemployment stabilization helps "Main Street" by providing consumption insurance. It hurts "Wall Street" by reducing precautionary saving and, thus, asset prices. On the aggregate level, household heterogeneity changes the transmission of monetary policy to consumption, but hardly to GDP. Central to this result is allowing for self-insurance and aggregate investment.</description><dc:date>2016-05-27T08:05:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1167: Doves for the Rich, Hawks for the Poor? Distributional Consequences of Monetary Policy</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-05-27T08:05:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161166"><title>IFDP 2016-1166: The Macroeconomic Impact of Financial and Uncertainty Shocks</title><link>/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161166</link><description>Dario Caldara, Cristina Fuentes-Albero, Simon Gilchrist and Egon Zakrajsek | The extraordinary events surrounding the Great Recession have cast a considerable doubt on the traditional sources of macroeconomic instability. In their place, economists have singled out financial and uncertainty shocks as potentially important drivers of economic fluctuations. Empirically distinguishing between these two types of shocks, however, is difficult because increases in economic uncertainty are strongly associated with a widening of credit spreads, an indication of a tightening in financial conditions. This paper uses the penalty function approach within the SVAR framework to examine the interaction between financial conditions and economic uncertainty and to trace out the impact of these two types of shocks on the economy. The results indicate that (1) financial shocks have a significant adverse effect on economic outcomes and that such shocks were an important source of cyclical fluctuations since the mid-1980; (2) uncertainty shocks, especially those implied by uncertainty proxies that do not rely on financial asset prices, are also an important source of macroeconomic disturbances; and (3) uncertainty shocks have an especially negative economic impact in situations where they elicit a concomitant tightening of financial conditions. Evidence suggests that the Great Recession was likely an acute manifestation of the toxic interaction between uncertainty and financial shocks.</description><dc:date>2016-05-25T16:25:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1166: The Macroeconomic Impact of Financial and Uncertainty Shocks</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-05-25T16:25:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161165"><title>IFDP 2016-1165: "It's Not You, It's Me": Breakups in U.S.-China Trade Relationships</title><link>/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161165</link><description>Ryan Monarch | Costs to switching suppliers can affect prices by discouraging buyer movements from high to low cost sellers. This paper uses confidential U.S. Customs data on U.S. importers and their Chinese exporters to investigate these costs. I find considerable barriers to supply chain adjustments: 45% of arm's-length importers keep their partner, and one-third of switching importers remain in the same city. Guided by these regularities, I propose and structurally estimate a dynamic discrete exporter choice model. Cost estimates are large and heterogeneous across products. These costs matter for trade prices: halving switching costs reduces the U.S.- China Import Price Index by 14.7%.</description><dc:date>2016-05-25T15:05:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1165: "It's Not You, It's Me": Breakups in U.S.-China Trade Relationships</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-05-25T15:05:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="/apps/fof/default.aspx"><title>IFDP 2016-1164: Relative Wealth Concerns, Executive Compensation, and Systemic Risk-Taking</title><link>/apps/fof/default.aspx</link><description>Qi Liu and Bo Sun | Given the recent empirical evidence on peer effects in CEO compensation, this paper theoretically examines how relative wealth concerns, in which a manager's satisfaction with his own compensation depends on the compensation of other managers, affect the equilibrium contracting strategy and managerial risk-taking. We find that such externalities can generate pay-for-luck as an efficient compensation vehicle in equilibrium. In expectation of pay-for-luck in other firms, tying managerial pay to luck provides insurance to managers against a compensation shortfall relative to executive peers during market fluctuations. When all firms pay for luck, we show that an effort-inducing mechanism exists: managers have additional incentives to exert effort in utilizing investment opportunities, which helps them keep up with their peers during industry movements. In addition, we show that compensation arrangements involving pay-for-luck that are efficient from the shareholders' perspective can nonetheless exacerbate aggregate fluctuations in the real economy by incentivizing excessive systemic risk-taking, especially in periods of heightened risk.</description><dc:date>2016-05-18T15:40:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1164: Relative Wealth Concerns, Executive Compensation, and Systemic Risk-Taking</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-05-18T15:40:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161163"><title>IFDP 2016-1163: Macroeconomic Dynamics Near the ZLB: A Tale of Two Countries</title><link>https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161163</link><description>S. Boragan Aruoba, Pablo Cuba-Borda, and Frank Schorfheide | We compute a sunspot equilibrium in an estimated small-scale New Keynesian model with a zero lower bound (ZLB) constraint on nominal interest rates and a full set of stochastic fundamental shocks. In this equilibrium a sunspot shock can move the economy from a regime in which inflation is close to the central bank's target to a regime in which the central bank misses its target, inflation rates are negative, and interest rates are close to zero with high probability. A nonlinear filter is used to examine whether the U.S. in the aftermath of the Great Recession and Japan in the late 1990s transitioned to a deflation regime. The results are somewhat sensitive to the model specification, but on balance, the answer is affirmative for Japan and negative for the U.S.</description><dc:date>2016-05-03T13:38:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1163: Macroeconomic Dynamics Near the ZLB: A Tale of Two Countries</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-05-03T13:38:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161162"><title>IFDP 2016-1162: The Macroeconomic Risks of Undesirably Low Inflation</title><link>https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161162</link><description>Jonas E. Arias, Christopher Erceg, and Mathias Trabandt | This paper investigates the macroeconomic risks associated with undesirably low inflation using a medium-sized New Keynesian model. We consider different causes of persistently low inflation, including a downward shift in long-run inflation expectations, a fall in nominal wage growth, and a favorable supply-side shock. We show that the macroeconomic effects of persistently low inflation depend crucially on its underlying cause, as well as on the extent to which monetary policy is constrained by the zero lower bound. Finally, we discuss policy options to mitigate these effects.</description><dc:date>2016-05-03T13:36:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1162: The Macroeconomic Risks of Undesirably Low Inflation</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-05-03T13:36:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item><item rdf:about="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161161"><title>IFDP 2016-1161: Bank Capital Pressures, Loan Substitutability, and Nonfinancial Employment</title><link>https://www.federalreserve.gov/econresdata/ifdp/2016/index.htm#20161161</link><description>Seung Jung Lee and Viktors Stebunovs | We exploit the cross-state, cross-time variation in bank tangible capital ratios--brought about by bank branch deregulation on a state-by-state basis--to identify the effects of bank capital pressures on employment and firm dynamics during two waves of changes in bank capital regulation. We show that stronger capital pressures temporarily slowed down growth in employment in industries that depend on external finance, retarding growth in the average size of firms rather than in the number of firms. Such effects were particularly strong for smaller firms that may not have had access to national capital and bank loan markets. Our findings indicate that a tightening of capital requirements may have significant real effects, in part because of the lack of substitutes for bank loans.</description><dc:date>2016-05-03T13:34:00-04:00</dc:date><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:publisher>FRB</dc:publisher><dcterms:valid>end=9999-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</dcterms:valid><cb:news><cb:simpleTitle>IFDP 2016-1161: Bank Capital Pressures, Loan Substitutability, and Nonfinancial Employment</cb:simpleTitle><cb:occurrenceDate>2016-05-03T13:34:00-04:00</cb:occurrenceDate><cb:keyword>IFDP</cb:keyword></cb:news></item></rdf:RDF>